Hello, my name is Hongchan
大家好 我是Hongchan
and today I'm going to talk about some thoughts
今天我要讲一讲
and considerations in building audio apps on the web.
开发 Web 音频应用的一些感想和注意事项
The goal of this presentation
本次演讲的目的
is to lay out some discussion topics
就是给大家展示一些
on web-based media production. slide-2
Web 媒体制作的讨论话题
Just to briefly introduce myself,
先做个简短的自我介绍
I'm the tech lead of the Chrome Web Audio team
我是Chrome Web Audio团队的技术主管
and the co-chair of W3C Audio Working Group. slide-3
以及 W3C 音频工作组的联合主席
Here's my question to you,
我先问大家一个问题
what are the things that you need to think about
如果你现在要开发一款网络音频应用
if you were to build a web audio app today? slide-4
你需要考虑哪些事情？
Obviously, the first thing you need to take a look at
显然 你首先要考虑的就是
is Web Audio API,
Web Audio API
but I'm not going to talk about how to use it here today. 16-p
但我今天不打算讨论如何使用它
It has been around for more than a decade
它已经存在十多年了
and we have plenty of code examples and tutorials out there.
我们有大量的代码实例和教程
Instead, I would like to discuss its architecture
相反 我想讨论一下它的架构
and performance characteristics. slide-5
以及工作特性
Two notes, first Web Audio API
要注意两点 首先 Web Audio API
is a graph-based audio programming environment.
是一个基于图形的音频编程环境
There are a handful of audio nodes
有一小部分音频节点
you can interconnect to create a graph. 24-p
可以相互连接形成图形
Secondly, the graph renderer
其次 图形渲染器
is run by a dedicated high priority thread
由专用的高级优先线程运行
which is usually a real-time thread. 27-p
它通常是个实时线程
This design was inevitable because the Web Audio API
这种设计是不可避免的 因为
is a part of the web platform. slide-6
Web Audio API 是 Web 平台的一部分
The processing audio streams directly
直接在应用的主线程上
on the application's main thread
处理音频流
causes a poor user experience in general.
通常会造成糟糕的用户体验
This is why the web audio node leaps on the main thread
这就是为什么 web 音频节点在主线程上
and the actual audio processing, I call them internals,
而实际的音频处理 我称之为内部节点
happens on a dedicated isolated thread. 35-p
在一个专用的独立线程上的原因
For better or worse, Web Audio API
不管怎样 Web Audio API
hides the low-level audio implementation
对开发人员隐藏了
away from the developer.
低级的音频实现
It means that you don't have to write on oscillator
这意味着你不必从零开始
or a filter or a compressor from scratch,
编写示波器 滤波器或压缩工具
it is provided by the implementation,
因为它已经提供给你了
but it also means that things can get complicated quickly
但这也意味着当你想接触裸机时
when you want to touch the bare metal
一切就会迅速变得复杂起来
such as implementing your own filter
比如用你自己的滤波器
that manipulates audio samples. slide-7
来处理音频样本
For that sort of use case,
对于那种用例
Web Audio API has Audio Worklet.
Web Audio API 有 AudioWorklet
With this object,
通过这个对象
you can write your own audio processing modules
你可以用 JavaScript 和 WebAssembly
with JavaScript and WebAssembly. slide-8
编写自己的音频处理模块
Another interesting aspect is that Web Audio API
另一有趣的方面是 Web Audio API
is a JavaScript API.
是一个 JavaScript API
As you already know,
大家都知道
JavaScript is a garbage collected language
JavaScript 是一种垃圾回收语言
with some controversial quirks
有一些颇具争议的小毛病
like typing and scoping and et cetera.
比如输入和作用域等等
When you are building a larger scale real world product,
当你开发大规模的现实世界产品时
you will encounter problems related
你会遇到与垃圾回收
to the garbage collection and performance. 59-p
和性能有关的问题
It's something you cannot control
这是不受你控制的
and it varies across browsers, but you have to be mindful. 61-p
不同浏览器中有所不同 但你必须注意
Technically, garbage collection
从技术上来说 垃圾回收
should not impact Web Audio API's renderer
不该影响 Web Audio API 的渲染器
because it runs on a different thread,
因为它在不同线程上运行
but that's not always the case.
但凡事都有例外
Even though your code is flawless,
即使你的代码完美无瑕
not creating any garbages,
不会产生任何垃圾
libraries that you're using might be wasteful,
但你所用的库可能会造成浪费
it might be inducing garbage collection.
这就可能造成垃圾回收
Creating too many objects at once
一次性创建太多对象
will eventually put pressure on the audio renderer
最终会给音频渲染器带来压力
because audio nodes are garbage collected objects,
因为音频节点是垃圾收回收的对象
even though internals are not,
虽然内部节点不是
but they are still associated together. slide-9
但它们依然关联在一起
What do you do?
那你该怎么办呢？
You inspect and profile the performance.
你要检查并分析它的性能
It gives you insights on when it happened
这能让你了解它何时发生
and how it happened. 78-p
以及如何发生
In Chrome, you can use the Web Audio perf toolkit
在 Chrome 你可以用 Web Audio 性能工具包
and that's my first offer today. slide-10
这是我今天的首个建议
First, the Web Audio DevTools panel.
首先 Web Audio 开发者工具面板
This is a very simple tool that allows you
这个简单的工具能让你
to monitor the health of the audio system
监控音频系统的健康状况
and its rendering capacity. 84-p
和它的渲染能力
If you're experiencing audio glitches,
如果你遇到音频故障
it's most likely either of two cases. 86-p
很可能是以下两种情况的一种
A: the callback timing is irregular,
第一种 回调时间不规律
this can happen when the renderer runs
当渲染器运行在低优先级线程时
on a lower priority thread 89-p
会发生这种现象
And B: the audio processing load
第二种 音频处理的负荷
goes beyond the CPU capacity.
超出了 CPU 的能力
This can happen for so many reasons,
造成这种情况的原因有很多
but in the end, you're trying to do too much
但到最后 你想做的太多了
and the callback misses its deadline. 94-p
回调错过了最后期限
The DevTools panel provides the metrics for both. slide-11
开发者工具面板为两者提供了指标
Secondly, we have the audio graph visualizer extension.
其次 我们有音频图形可视化拓展
This is the most recent addition to our toolkit.
这是最新添加到我们工具包里的
This is not shipped with Chrome,
不是 Chrome 自带的
so you will have to install it from the Chrome Web Store,
所以 你必须从 Chrome 网络商店安装
which is just one time process. 100-p
只需要安装一次即可
This tool is useful in at least two cases.
这个工具至少能用在两种情况下
First, a larger scale web audio application
首先 更大规模的网络音频应用
typically constructs and destroys a lot of audio nodes.
通常能构建并破坏许多音频节点
It's really hard to spot a wrong connection between them
通过读取源代码很难发现它们之间的
by reading the source code. 105-p
连接错误
The visualization is immensely better
而可视化能更加准确地
in pinpointing a mistake. 107-p
定位错误
Secondly, it allows you to understand
其次 它能让你了解
the level of a redundancy of your graph.
你的图形的冗余程度
You might be creating too many gain nodes for no reason.
你可能无缘无故地创建了太多增益节点
It is very common technique using several gain nodes
用几个增益节点来结束一个子图
to wrap a subgraph. 112-p
是很常见的技术
Also, there might be an orphaned node that is created,
此外 还可能创建出孤立节点
but not connected to anything,
但它不与任何对象相连
which is surprisingly common as well. slide-12
这也是非常普遍的
Lastly, you can use a Chrome's Tracing tool.
最后 你可以用 Chrome 的跟踪工具
This is a bit more involved
这比之前的选项
compared to the previous options,
要复杂得多
but it is comprehensive and it's full of insights. 119-p
但它更全面 能洞悉一切
You can use this by going to chrome://tracing.
你可以去 chrome://tracing 这里使用
I suggest reading the article that I wrote
我建议大家读一下我写的文章
to explain how to use it for a audio application.
上面解释了如何在音频应用中使用它
You can just Google "Profiling web audio apps." 123-p
你可以搜索 “Web Audio 分析应用”
This tool is also important for two reasons.
这个工具也很重要 原因有两个
First, this shows exactly when things went down
首先 它显示了事情发生的确切时间
and how they happened.
以及它们如何发生
You will be able to see when an audio stream glitches
你能知道音频流出现故障的时间
like buffer underruns, and make an informed guess about why. 128-p
比如缓存欠载 并对原因做出合理猜测
Secondly, this is incredibly useful
其次 你与 Chromium 的
when you communicate with Chromium engineers.
工程师沟通时 它非常有用
It is very likely
我们的设置
that we don't have the exact same setup with you,
很可能跟你的不是完全一样的
so some reproduction of the issue might be impossible.
所以很难重现你遇到的问题
So, when fixing bugs, exchanging a trace file
所以 修复漏洞时 与我们交换跟踪文件
with us really helps the communication. slide-13
真的有助于沟通
Okay, let's shift gears
好了 我们换个话题
and talk about other issues
讨论一下别的问题
like device latency and user privacy. slide-14
比如设备延迟和用户隐私
As you're building a client side application,
在开发客户端应用程序时
like an instrument or an audio recorder,
例如工具或录音编辑软件
editor, or a DAW, soon you will realize
或数字音频工作站 你很快会意识到
that the lack of access to audio device
无法使用音频设备
is a big gap between the web and the native platform. 143-p
是网络和本地平台之间的巨大差别
It means that device related settings,
它意味着与设备相关的设置
such as number of channels, sample rate, and buffer size
例如频道数量 采样速度和缓冲的大小
are not readily available for your application. 146-p
对你的应用来说都很难即时获得
We, browser implementers, actually are aware of that
作为浏览器的开发者 我们都知道
that this is a huge pain point for developers,
这对开发者来说是个很大的痛点
but it is not without a reason. 149-p
但是事出有因
This device related information can be exploited
这个设备相关的信息可以被广告商
by advertisers or attackers to infer the user's identity.
或攻击者用来推断用户的身份
This technique is called fingerprinting
这种技术叫做指纹识别
and it is one of the reason
这也是网络上
that we cannot have nice things on the web. 154-p
没有好东西的原因
There are of course,
当然了
countermeasures to this type of exploitation,
我们有针对这种滥用的反制措施
a constraint-based API pattern for example.
例如 基于约束的API模式
The app can make an inquiry
应用可以请求访问
and the platform will accept or reject it
平台会根据目前客户端的能力
depending on the current client's capability. 160-p
接受或拒绝访问
It's like asking, "Hey, my app needs four channels
这就像问“我的应用需要4个48k频道
at 48k and lowest possible latency."
以及尽可能低的延迟”
And the platform will say yes or no. 163-p
平台会接受或拒绝
That way, it is much harder to sneak in
这样 就更难通过偷渡式指纹识别
with a drive-by fingerprinting and at the same time,
偷偷溜进去 与此同时
we don't lose much of API usability. 166-p
我们也不会失去过多API可用性
Protecting user privacy was considered a hassle
保护用户隐私是一件麻烦事
and it was definitely a limiting factor of a web platform,
它绝对是网络平台的限制因素之一
but I believe so-called privacy over API design
但我觉得 API 设计中的所谓隐私
is gradually becoming a norm, even on the native platforms. 170-p
正逐渐成为一种规范 即使在本地平台
These days, you will find similar protection mechanisms
目前 你会发现类似的保护机制
like a system-wide permission UI for microphone access
例如在苹果或微软系统中使用麦克风时
in other operating system like MacOS or Windows. slide-15
出现的全系统请求允许的界面
Now let's talk a little bit about latency.
我们现在来谈谈延迟
I'm well aware that this is a thorny issue
我很清楚涉及到网络平台
when it comes to web platform
这就变成了一个复杂的问题
and at least for Chrome Web Audio,
至少对于 Chrome Web Audio 来说
we are not particularly doing well
我们的音频延迟方面
in audio latency department. 179-p
做得不是很好
For audio production apps,
对于音频制作应用来说
the latency is important at least for two reasons.
延迟很重要的原因有两个
First, the minimum latency possible matters
首先 当你在录音或监听时
when you're recording or monitoring,
尽可能减少延迟就变得很重要
but also accurate latency reporting from the platform
而且来自平台的精准的延迟报告
is critical for compensating audio after the fact. 185-p
对于事后的音频补偿也非常重要
But it's a tricky problem for browsers.
但这对浏览器来说很棘手
The browser needs to support a variety of configurations
浏览器需要在各种各样的平台上
on many different platforms.
支持很多配置
It means that we are spreading thin
这意味着我们可能顾此失彼
and might be missing
可能会缺乏
some obvious platform specific optimizations. 191-p
一些明显的针对平台的特定优化
When seasoned audio developers
当经验丰富的音频开发者
jump in Chrome's audio infrastructure, point out some problems,
投入 Chrome 音频的基础建设 指出问题时
we are always grateful for that
我们一直对此很感激
and that happened actually several times in the past. 195-p
这种情况在过去发生好几次了
Also, web audio is not the only audio API on the platform.
此外 Web Audio 不是平台唯一的音频 API
We're about to see a media element.
WebRTC 和媒体元件
In Chrome, they all also share the same audio infrastructure
在 Chrome 里，它们也与 Web Audio 有相同的
with web audio.
基础建设
This makes it hard to bring a big change
这让我们很难做出只对 Web Audio 有益
that only benefits web audio and not others. 201-p
却对别的工具无益的巨大变革
RTC and media usually focus on the resilience,
实时通讯和媒体通常关注的是弹性
which means more buffering,
也就是更多的缓冲
but web audio cares more about the low-latency
但Web Audio更在意低延迟
and interactivity, which means less buffering.
和交互性 也就是更少的缓冲
This conflict makes it hard
这种冲突使我们更难应用
to apply the aggressive optimization
只对Web Audio
that only benefits web audio. slide-16
有利的优化
What's the reality today? 209-p
现在的情况如何呢？
For web audio, you have to usually get your media
对于网络音频 需要用getUserMedia
for microphone input and the output simply goes
进行麦克风输入 然后直接输出到
to the system default audio device. 212-p
系统默认的音频设备
But what if you want to use an audio device
但你要是想用其他音频设备
other than a default one?
而不是默认的呢？
The only known solution is to use the audio element.
唯一已知的解决方案就是使用音频元件
By streaming the web audio output to an audio element
通过将 Web Audio 输出传输到特定设备的
with the selected device. 217-p
音频元件上
Here, streaming usually means
传输通常意味着
there are some buffering going on somewhere down there.
某些地方会进行一些缓冲
That can't be good for latency. slide-17
这会导致很大的延迟
What can we do about it?
我们能做点什么呢？
The Audio Working Group is currently working
音频工作组目前正在致力于
to create a new API that allows you
创建一个新的API
to select the audio output device for a audio context.
可以让你为音频选择输出设备
Theoretically, this will guarantee the code path
理论上来说 这将确保代码路径
that minimizes the output latency. 226-p
将输出延迟最小化
Also, one can dream about creating new API
此外 也有人想为输入设备选择
for input device selection as well.
创建一个新的API
I'm curious how many people would want that.
我很好奇会有多少人想要这个
Please let me know what you think. slide-18
请不要吝惜你的看法
That's all I have for today and here's the conclusion. slide-19
以上就是今天的全部内容 下面是总结
We talked about the design
我们谈到了
and the architecture of Web Audio API
Web Audio API 的设计和架构
and also I introduced the Web Audio perf ToolKit
我还介绍了 Chrome 的 Web Audio
from Chrome, and also we discussed the problems
性能工具包 而且我们还讨论了
in device access and latency. 236-p
设备访问和延迟
By all means, this is just a conversation starter,
无论如何 这只是抛砖引玉
not a comprehensive guideline. slide-20
不是全面的指南
With that, I would like to invite you to a survey,
因此 我想邀请大家参加一项调查
so we, browser implementers,
以便我们浏览器的开发者
can understand your needs better.
了解大家的需求
Here's a link. 242-p
这是链接
Lastly, my chrome tech lead
最后 作为 Chrome 的技术主管
hat on, building a healthy ecosystem
为 Web Audio 开发健康的生态系统
for web audio is my job and I'm open to have a chat
是我的职责所在 我愿意与任何
with anyone who is interested in partnership with my team. 246-p
感兴趣与我的团队合作的人建立沟通
Please feel free to email me or DM me on Twitter.
欢迎大家给我发邮件或推特私信我
Thank you for watching.
感谢大家的观看
Be safe and stay healthy.
祝大家健康平安